pitneybowessmallbusiness.com 2012-11-19

# Privacy Statement for Pitney Bowes Small Business

Home >> About Us >> Privacy Statement

This Privacy Statement is effective as of July 6, 2010. 

We are committed to respecting the privacy of visitors to our websites.  We have created this Privacy Statement to describe how our websites operate, and how we collect, use, and share information gathered from our online visitors.

This Privacy Statement applies to <http://www.pb.com/> and all other external websites, web-hosted applications, web pages and/or web properties owned and operated by Pitney Bowes, Pitney Bowes business units and Pitney Bowes subsidiaries (collectively referred to as "Pitney Bowes" and individually as a "Pitney Bowes company") referred to in this statement as "Sites," except to the extent such other websites contain their own Privacy Statement. 

The following topics are presented in this Privacy Statement:

  1. Collecting Personal Information from Website Visitors
  2. Collecting Other Information
  3. Using Personal Information
  4. Sharing Personal Information
  5. Protecting Personal Information
  6. Transferring Personal Information to Other Countries
  7. Visiting Non-Pitney Bowes Websites
  8. Safe Harbor
  9. Country-Specific Requirements
  10. Your Choices
  11. Our Right to Change this Privacy Statement

**1\. Collecting Personal Information from Website Visitors**

In order to provide you with access to certain services or data within our Sites, we may require that you provide certain personal information. This information may include your name, postal address, telephone number, fax number, e-mail address, subscriber name or screen name, password used to access our services, method of payment, and, if applicable, payment information, such as credit card number and expiration date associated with online purchases. 

In addition, we collect (1) the e-mail addresses of visitors that communicate with us via e-mail, post messages to our bulletin boards or post messages to our chat groups, and (2) information provided by visitors in sales orders, registration forms, surveys, contest entries, and other submissions to us.

We also collect and track automatically (1) the home server domain names, IP addresses, type of client computer, and type of web browser of visitors to our Sites, and (2) aggregate and specific information on what pages visitors access. 

**2\. Collecting Other Information**

Pitney Bowes uses several automatic data collection tools and techniques including cookies, clickstream, and web beacons.

Cookies   
Some of our Sites use a technology called "cookies" so that we can better serve visitors when they purchase a product on our Sites, request additional information about our company, products or services, or participate in various activities posted

on our Sites. A cookie is a bit of text that is placed on a user's computer hard drive when certain websites are visited. These cookies may be placed by us or by third party vendors and are used to obtain data such as user-name, shopping cart contents, and web pages or advertisements viewed by the visitor. When the visitor revisits our Sites, we can recognize the visitor by the Internet cookie and customize the visitor's experience accordingly. 

You can set your browser to provide notice whenever a cookie is received, which gives you the opportunity to decide whether to accept it or not.  Without cookies, however, you may not be able to take full advantage of all our Site features. For example, if you turn off cookies or refuse them, you will not be able to make purchases on our Sites. 

Clickstream  
Certain of our Sites may collect information about the "clickstream" of our customers during their visit to our Sites. This clickstream data contains the pages the visitors came from, the navigational paths they took, and the areas of the Sites they visited. 

From time to time, we track such information inside and outside of our Sites.  Additionally, we may from time to time track and match clickstream data with personal information you provide to us in order to deliver content and other offerings - i.e., products and services that might improve your customer experience. 

Web Beacon  
Certain email communications you may receive from us may contain "web beacons."   Web beacons consist of a line of code on our Sites that delivers a small graphic image from another website or third-party ad server. The web beacon may not be visible as it is generally a 1x1 pixel that is often designed to blend into the background of a web page. Web beacons allow third parties to obtain information such as the IP address of the computer that downloaded the page on which the web beacon appears, the URL of the page on which the web beacon appears, the time the page containing the web beacon was viewed, the type of browser used to view the page and the information in cookies set by the third party.  We may use web beacons for activities such as monitoring the effectiveness of ad banners in our email distributions. 

**3\. Using Personal Information**

Personal information we collect through our Sites will be used to, among other things, fulfill orders and requests for information, for marketing and promoting products and services of Pitney Bowes and other entities that we believe you may find of interest, for feedback purposes, for a statistical analysis of users' behavior, for product development or enhancement, for content improvement, to notify you of upcoming events and to customize content and layout of our Sites. Names, postal and e-mail addresses, and phone numbers collected through our Sites may be used to contact you regarding products and services and upcoming events we believe you might find of interest. 

We also may use the personal information you provide for Pitney Bowes internal purposes, such as administration and operation of our Sites, data analytics, and compliance with our legal obligations, policies and procedures.

**4\. Sharing Personal Information**

We do not share or otherwise disclose personal information about our Site visitors, except as described here or where permitted by law.  Pitney Bowes may share your personal information within the Pitney Bowes family of businesses and with third parties that perform services for us or on our behalf (for example, credit card companies, financial institutions, shipping companies, consultants, advisors and market research firms).  Service providers and suppliers are required to keep confidential and secure the personal information received from us and may not use it for any other purpose other than as originally intended.    We also may disclose personal information when, in our judgment, we believe it is necessary or appropriate to prevent fraud, injury, or harm to persons or property, to protect our rights or the rights of others, or as otherwise required by applicable law, regulation or legal process. 

We also may provide, rent, sell or otherwise share the personal information we collect from you for marketing campaigns conducted by us or other companies or organizations that offer products or services we believe may be of interest to our customers. Depending upon local law, you may either opt in or opt out of having your personal information used and/or shared for marketing purposes in the Your Choices section below. If you are in California, please see the United States section under Country-Specific Requirements regarding the sharing of your personal information among our affiliated companies for marketing purposes. 

Personal information may also be transferred in connection with a business transition such as a merger, acquisition, insolvency, or asset sale involving any Pitney Bowes business or asset to which the information pertains.  Should such a sale or transfer occur, we will use reasonable efforts to direct the transferee to use personal information you have provided to us in a manner that is consistent with our Privacy Statement.

**5\. Protecting Personal Information**

We maintain reasonable administrative, technical and physical safeguards to protect against loss, misuse or unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration or destruction of personal information you provide on our Sites.

**6\. Transferring Personal Information to Other Countries**

Where permitted by local laws and regulatory requirements, we may transfer the personal information we collect on our Sites to other countries where we, and our service providers, do business, but we will do so only for the purposes described above. When we transfer your personal information to other countries, we will protect that information as described within this Privacy Statement unless otherwise required by applicable laws.

**7\. Visiting Non-Pitney Bowes Websites**

This privacy statement applies solely to information collected during your use of our Sites. Our Sites may contain links to other websites that may operate independently from Pitney Bowes.  These and other websites may also reference or link to our Sites.

Pitney Bowes is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such other non-Pitney Bowes websites.  We encourage you to be aware of the privacy statements of each and every website with which you may interact. 

**8\. Safe Harbor**

The following Pitney Bowes companies adhere to the U.S. Safe Harbor privacy principles:

  * Pitney Bowes Software Inc.

9\. Country-Specific Requirements

Pitney Bowes Inc. is a global corporation with subsidiary companies located around the world.  This Privacy Statement establishes our global principles for the collection, use and disclosure of information gathered through our Sites.   The country in which you are doing business with us or where the Site you are visiting is located/hosted may have specific requirements concerning personal information. 

**10\. Your Choices**

If you wish to update or remove your personal information, opt out from receiving, or opt in to receive, marketing communications from us please do so by indicating your preferences on the relevant Site or by contacting us at the mail or email address below.  For Pitney Bowes My Account users, please log in to My Account and see "Edit e-mail preferences".

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Statement, please contact us at: 

Pitney Bowes Privacy Office  
1 Elmcroft Road  
Stamford, CT USA 06926-0700 

or

[privacyoffice@pb.com](mailto:privacyoffice@pb.com) Where required by law, you may request access to your personal information that we maintain.  As permitted by law, we may charge a reasonable fee for providing access to personal information, but we do not charge for lodging a request for access. 

**11\. Our Right to Change this Privacy Statement**

This Privacy Statement may be updated periodically and without prior notice to you to reflect changes in our online information practices. We will indicate at the top of the statement when it was most recently updated. We recommend that you visit our Privacy Statement page whenever you visit our Sites so that you are aware of any changes.
